## Xiaotian Han

E-mail: han@tamu.edu

Homepage: ahxt.github.io

Ph.D. Student Department of Computer Science & Engineering Texas A&M University

### **Research Interests**

I am a 4th-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering at Texas A&M University. I am working at the DATA Lab under the supervision of Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu. My research focuses on graph learning, fairness in machine learning, and automated machine learning. Specifically, my research lies in the following topics:

- Graph Learning: large-scale graph neural networks, graph augmentation
- Fairness: egocentric fairness and structure fairness in graph neural network
- LLMs for Healthcare: large language models for clinical text mining

### **Education**

**Texas A&M University**, College Station, TX, USA Sep 2019 – Dec 2023 (Expected)

Ph.D. students, Department of Computer Science & Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Xia (Ben) Hu

**Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications**, Beijing, CHINA Sep 2016 – June 2019

M.S. in Computer Science Advisor: Prof. Chuan Shi

Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong, CHINA Sep 2011 – June 2015

B.S. in Information and Communication Engineering

## **Professional Experiences**

Meta, Menlo Park, CA Sept 2022 – present

Research Intern

Understanding graph neural networks

Mentor: Qifan Wang

Snap Research, Seattle, WA May 2022 - Aug 2022

Research Intern

Efficient large-scale graph neural networks

Mentor: Neil Shah

Microsoft Research Asian (MSRA), Beijing, China

March 2019 - Jun 2019

Research Intern

Hyperparameter search with Bayesian optimization

Alibaba Group, Hangzhou, China

June 2018 - Sep 2018

Research Intern, Search Business Department

Query recommendation

# **Publications** [Google Scholar]

[ICLR 2023] MLPInit: Embarrassingly Simple GNN Training Acceleration with MLP Initialization

Xiaotian Han, Tong Zhao, Yozen Liu, Xia Hu, Neil Shah

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2023

[ICML 2022] G-Mixup: Graph Augmentation for Graph Classification

**Xiaotian Han**, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu *International Conference on Machine Learning* (**ICML**), 2022

**Outstanding Paper Award** 

<sup>\*</sup> indicates equal contribution.

[ICLR 2022] Generalized Demographic Parity for Group Fairness

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Fan Yang, Xia Hu, International Conference on Learning Representations (**ICLR**), 2022

[WWW 2022] Graph Representation Learning via Unsupervised Rate Reduction Maximization

Xiaotian Han, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Xia Hu

The Web Conference (**WWW**), 2022

[Recsys 2020] AutoRec: An Automated Recommender System

Ting-Hsiang Wang, Qingquan Song, **Xiaotian Han**, Zirui Liu, Jin Haifeng, Xia Hu

ACM Conference on Recommender Systems (Recsys), 2020

[AAAI 2020] FlowScope: Spotting Money Laundering Based on Graphs,

Xiangfeng Li, Shenghua Liu, Zifeng Li, Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Bryan Hooi, He Huang, Xueqi Cheng

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2020

[WWWJ 2020] Embedding Geographic Information for Anomalous Trajectory Detection

Ding Xiao, Li Song, Ruijia Wang, **Xiaotian Han**, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi

World Wide Web, 2020

[KDD 2020] Metapath-guided Heterogeneous Graph Neural Network for Intent Recommendation

Shaohua Fan, Junxiong Zhu, **Xiaotian Han**, Chuan Shi, Linmei Hu, Biyu Ma, Yongliang Li

SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2019

[TKDE 2019] Deep Collaborative Filtering with Multi-aspect Information in Heterogeneous Networks

Chuan Shi, Xiaotian Han, Li Song, Xiao Wang, Senzhang Wang, Junping Du, Philip, S Yu

IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (**TKDE**), 2019

[APWeb 2018] Representation Learning with Depth and Breadth for Recommendation using Multi-view Data

Xiaotian Han, Chuan Shi, Lei Zheng, Philip, S Yu, Jianxin Li, Yuanfu Lu

APWeb-WAIM International Joint Conference on Web and Big Data (APWeb-WAIM), 2018

[IJCAI 2018] Aspect-Level Deep Collaborative Filtering via Heterogeneous Information Networks

**Xiaotian Han**, Chuan Shi, Senzhang Wang, Philip, S Yu, Li Song International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (**IJCAI**), 2018

[ADMA 2018] Anomalous Trajectory Detection Using Recurrent Neural Network

Li Song, Ruijia Wang, Ding Xiao, **Xiaotian Han**, Yanan Cai, Chuan Shi

International Conference on Advanced Data Mining and Applications (ADMA), 2018

Best Paper Awards

[Under review] Do We Really Achieve Fairness with Explicit Sensitive Attributes?

**Xiaotian Han**, Zhimeng Jiang, Ninghao Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Marginal Nodes Matter: Towards Structure Fairness in Graphs

Xiaotian Han, Kaixiong Zhou, Ting-Hsiang Wang, Jundong Li, Fei Wang, Na Zou

2022

[Under review] Retiring  $\Delta DP$ : New Distribution-Level Metrics for Demographic Parity

Xiaotian Han\*, Zhimeng Jiang\*, Hongye Jin, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Qifan Wang, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Fair Graph Message Passing with Transparency

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Topology Matters in Fair Graph Learning: a Theoretical Pilot Study

Zhimeng Jiang, **Xiaotian Han**, Chao Fan, Zirui Liu, Xiao Huang, Na Zou, Ali Mostafavi, Xia Hu

2022

[Under review] Does Synthetic Data Generation of LLMs Help Clinical Text Mining?

Ruixiang Tang\*, Xiaotian Han\*, Xiaoqian Jiang, Xia Hu

2023

### **Professional Services**

#### **Program Committee Member/Reviewer**

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI)	2021,2022,2023
International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence( <b>IJCAI</b> )  The ACM Web Conference ( <b>WWW</b> )	2021,2023 2023
ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining ( <b>KDD</b> )	2023
International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)	2022
Volunteer	
International Conference on Machine Learning ( <b>ICML</b> )	2022
Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAAC	<b>CL</b> ) 2022
Session Chair	
International Conference on Machine Learning ( <b>ICML</b> )	2022
Scholarships, Awards, & Honors	
Outstanding Paper Award, ICML2022	2022
Travel Grant, Department of CSE, Texas A&M University,	2022
Travel Award, ICML2022	2022
Outstanding Reviewer Award, ICML2022	2022
Best Reviewer Award, CCF Transactions on Pervasive Computing and Interaction	2019
National Graduate Scholarship, Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications	2018
Best Paper Awards, International Conference on Advanced Data Mining and Applications	2018

Last updated on March 09, 2023